Matthew Gazzano Senior Data Analyst

Contact

Mattgazzano.com

in linkedin.com/matthewgazzano

Mattgazzano@gmail.com

Greater NYC Metropolitan Area

About

Well-rounded Senior level Data Analyst specializing in transactional modeling, SQL, and data visualization in the information services industry. Experience in a front facing role with the ability to compile technical reports and present them to non-technical users that provide meaning to the business. Background in project management within a startup environment, possessing great organization & communication skills that deliver quantifiable results.

Education

Montclair State University

Montclair, NJ

Feliciano School of Business — AACSB Accredited

Master of Science in Business Analytics (MSBA) – Part Time – 4.0 Class of 2022

Ramapo College of New Jersey

Mahwah, NJ

Anisfield School of Business - AACSB Accredited

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration: Marketing - 3.6 January 2018

Experience

Dow Jones New York, NY

Senior Data Analyst, FP&A — Business Intelligence

May 2022 - Present

- Develop and support self-servicing dashboards that identify monthly revenue, net gains / losses, and forecasted opportunities.
- Use Python and SQL to help automate reporting efforts through identifying workflow optimizations.
- Support traffic and product teams to identify usage metrics via Adobe Analytics.

Health Monitor Network

Montvale, NI

Senior Bl Analyst June 2020 – May 2022

• Own standardized dashboarding for C-level management on status of digital product network & ad deployment of client programs

- Team lead for developing & maintaining data pipeline inside data warehouse environment (Google BigQuery)
- Transactional modeling via CRM & ERP systems to capture field service data (Zoho CRM / NetSuite ERP)
- Communicating the meaning behind results and providing actionable recommendations to the organization

Digital Operations Analyst January 2018 – June 2020

- Produce weekly and ad hoc reporting on work orders that identify success and challenges on field service projects
- Develop, execute, and maintain standard operating procedures to deliver on sponsor programs across all digital products in network
- Optimize and coordinate the input and output of project deliverable data in CRM database
- Onboard new vendors with current processes and hold them accountable for delivery through tracking performance metrics

Skills / Applications



- Database Software: Google BigQuery, MySQL, MS Access, Oracle Express
- Microsoft Excel: Advanced Functions (XLOOKUP/VLOOKUP, COUNTIFS) Power Query Power Pivot ODBC Pivot Tables VBA / Macros
- **Python**: Pandas Numpy Seaborn Matplotlib Beautiful Soup Selenium Requests / API pulls
- Data Visualization: Tableau Power BI Google Data Studio

Published Musician (drummer) Can be found on Spotify!